This story is fiction. The names of people,
places and groups are imaginary.
Obey traffic rules and drive safely.
Initial
Raise up your hands　高く [Everybody gonna tell you I can't stop]
Raise up your hands high.
(Everybody now raise your hands)
Take hold, there's a brand new tomorrow.
掴め　Brand new tomorrow [You don't stop]
(You don't stop)
風の中で　自分を知る　ずっと最高のDreamだろう
It's a beautiful eternal dream...
...where you learn about yourself.
(Let's go)
Oh[Let's go] Oh[Let's go]
Oh
Oh (Let's go)
Oh raise up you can't stop
Oh, raise up your hands now.
If you think you're lucky just to be alive go for the highest stake in the gamble.
生きてるだけで何やろうかな
Gamble on　迫る鼓動にテンバリ
同じMission　同じ一生
Same mission creates similar lives.
But your passion for your dream will make a difference.
どんだけ夢熱いかが勝負だろ
You can never use the escalator.
Escalator　無しの永遠
But you can build up your strength, yeah yeah.
足腰鍛え　Let's begin yeah
You must eventually climb the stairs.
どうせのぼる階段
心こっちにCustomizeしちゃえばいい
Customize them the way you like.
Intense days go by.
削られて　過ぎる毎日[But you know]
Intense days go by. (But you know?)
攻めがいのあるGameと　笑い飛ばして
Just laugh it off, 'cause it's a game worth competing.
Let's see how fast you can do it
Let's see how fast you can do it.
Raise up your hands　ずっと [Everybody gonna tell you I can't stop]
Raise up your hands forever.
(Everybody now raise your hands up)
Run, sleepless challenger.
走れ　Sleepless challenger [You don't stop]
(You don't stop)
今に生きる　理由を探す
It's a quest of the never-ending dream...
...where you now search for the reason to live.
夢尽きないQuest
(Let's go)
Oh[Let's go] Oh[Let's go]
Oh
Oh (Let's go)
Oh, raise up your hands now.
Oh raise up you can't stop
あーれれ  ついに降ってきちゃいましたよ
Oh man, it's finally starting to rain.
Really ?
本当か
Yeah, it's coming down really hard.
あぁ　結構本降りだな
この後予報ではどうなんっすか
What does the forecast say ?
We can't trust it, especially when
it involves mountain weather.
当てにならないよ　予報なんて  山の天気だし
中途半端の路面が一番困るんだよな
The half-wet surface will be tricky.
濡れるなら濡れる　乾くなら乾く
Either full wet or full dry is better.
どっちかにしてもらわないと
心配いらねーよ  どっちかっていえば　コンディション悪いほうが俺はいいんだ
No need to worry.
I kinda prefer difficult conditions.
I get more excited as the
accelerator work gets more severe.
アクセルワークがシビアならシビアのほどがわくわくするからな
I don't hate wet roads either.
俺も濡れて滑る路面は嫌じゃないですよ
People say it's scary because you
don't know when you'll start to skid.
みんな滑るか滑らないか分からなくて怖いって言うけど
俺　86乗っててそんなこと思ったことないし
But I've never felt like that
while driving my Eight-Six.
I know how much I'll skid before entering a corner, so I just drive like I usually do.
コーナーに入る前からどんぐらい滑るかわかるから　いつも普通に走るだけです
ふん　生意気
Show off.
俺のおかずとった　それ大事に残しといたのに
That's my main dish !
I was saving it for later !
It rained after all.
やはり雨か　しかたあるまい　こればかりは天の意思
We can't do anything about God's will.
悪条件こそゼロ理論の真骨頂なんだ
Poor conditions are
perfect for my Zero theory.
何が起こるか予測不可能な公道バトルには　相応しい演出だろう
This is a suitable setup for a street
race where everything is unpredictable.
それにしても　高橋良介
Besides, that Takahashi Ryosuke...
あの男には特別な何かを感じる
I sense something special about that guy.
でかく　広く　深く　やさしい
Open, wide, deep, and gentle...
なのになぜだ　あの男が漂わせる切なさが
So then why does he seem
to hold such sadness ?
あれ　良介　ずいぶん早いな
Hey, Ryosuke, you're up early.
三時間も寝られれば何とかなるさ
I can manage even with
only three hours of sleep.
それより　文浩　面白いぜ　スパイラルの池田
Besides that, Fumihiro, Spiral's
Ikeda is one interesting guy.
うん　サイトで「ゼロ理論」という自分のドライビングについて　公表しているんだけど
He published his Zero theory for driving
on his site, and it's quite unique.
これがなかなかユニークで　俺と共感できる部分が多くて　興味深い
It's interesting because there
are so many similarities to mine.
公道最速理論と
With your theory of fastest street driving ?
この相手なら　啓介は苦戦する
Keisuke will have a hard time.
It's not going to be
easy for him to win.
簡単には勝たせてくれないだろう
おいおい　勝算はあるんだろう
We have a chance of winning, don't we ?
Sure. It's my job to find it.
勿論　それを見つけるのが俺の仕事だ
Mindset of Nothingness (Zero)
やれやれ　雨になっちまったか　箱根もやっぱり雨なんだろうな
Geez, it's raining.
It must be the same in Hakone.
嫌だな　雨の峠詰めは　いつ滑るか分からないし　ブレーキも効かないし
I hate tackling mountain passes in the rain.
I can never tell when my car is going to skid,
and the brakes don't work like they should.
おまけに視界も悪いし
Visibility is poor, too.
あれ不思議だよな　夜の雨って　ヘッドライトつけてても
It's really strange.
Night rain makes everything so dark,
even with the headlights on.
何もかも黒々と見えて　ほんっとに真っ暗になっちまうんだから
晴れてる時の半分以下だと思うよ　見えるの
I think you can only see half
of what you see on a clear night.
そうでなくても　ワイパーで視界遮られてるのに
On top of that, the wipers block the view.
何が怖いって　見えないことほどこわいものはないよ
Nothing scares me more
than losing the ability to see.
そう言えば　前にほら　俺拓海の86に乗って　雨のバトルを体験したことがあるじゃないですか
Speaking of which...
...remember when I got to ride in Takumi's
Eight-Six when he fought a rain battle at night ?
あぁ　あの時の拓海は鮮やかだったな　ぶっちぎりだったもんな
Yeah, Takumi was incredible that time.
He totally owned his opponent
with extraordinary speed.
異次元のスピードだよあれは
俺　リアシートで衝撃的な拓海のハンドル捌きを見ていたんですけど
I was watching Takumi's impressive
steering work from the rear seat.
I wondered why he didn't crash,
even though he couldn't see a thing.
一番思ったのは　何も見えないのに　なんで事故らないのかってことなんですよ
アクセルべた踏みだし　車横にして　とんでもないスピードでコーナー飛び込むし
He was going flat out, and entered the
corner sideways at incredible speed.
あの恐ろさはとても口では　言い表せませんよ
I can't express how scary it was.
Your facial expression
is more scary than that.
おまえの顔のほうが怖い
俺には分かる　失神したこともあるし
I know that fear, too.
I fainted from it once.
あれはもう運転技術の問題じゃなくて　もっと特殊な能力ですよ
It's more than just driving
skills, it's something special.
拓海には見えるんだと思う
I think Takumi can see...
Like, he has some special...
なんか特別な　もう一つの目があって　その目でクリアに視界を捉えてるんじゃないのかな
Like he has another eye, and that he can
clearly see his surroundings with it or something.
だから俺　雨が降ることは　拓海にとって不利なことじゃない気がするんですよ
That's why I don't think rain
will put him in a difficult position.
ストップ
Stop.
どうですか　路面は
How's the surface ?
I didn't see any water flowing across it.
水が流れているところはない　コース全域でほとんど止んでるし
The rain has stopped in almost
every part of the course.
このままもう降らないんじゃないかな
I think it'll stay like that.
予報でも強く降ることはないって言ってたし　路面の状態もほぼ現状維持と考えていいんじゃないか
The forecast didn't anticipate heavy rain, so
I think the road conditions will remain the same.
よし　ハーフウェットのBパターンの組み合わせで行こう
Okay, we'll go with the half wet pattern B.
啓介　霧は出ていたか
Keisuke, did you see any fog ?
Well, it was misty here and there...
そうだな　ところどころもやっていたけど　視界を妨げるほどじゃない
...but not thick enough to block my view.
そうか
I see.
もう時間か
Is it time already ?
いつも思うんですけど　瞑想の時は何を考えてるんですか
I always wonder what's on your
mind whenever you meditate.
何も考えないさ
Nothing at all.
Eh ?
えぇ
頭の中を空っぽにするのが瞑想だからな
To meditate is to empty your mind.
今回もあえて作戦は何もない
I intentionally didn't come up
with any plans for this race.
Desire for victory exposes human weakness.
勝ちたいと思う心は人間の弱さに繋がっていくんだ
俺はただ　車が持っている最高の状態を引き出すだけだ
I'll just try to bring the
very best out of my car.
それができたとき　結果は後で付いてくる
When I manage to do so,
the result will follow.
What I need is a mindset of Zero.
必要なのはゼロの心だ
一本目は俺が先攻する　有料道路の下のトンネルを潜ったら　フルスロットルだ
I'll be the lead for the first run.
As soon as we pass under the
tollway overpass, go full throttle.
Let's begin.
始めよう
いよいよ始まるな　プロD対スパイラル
Pro-D and Spiral's match is about to begin.
Too bad the road is wet.
残念なのは路面が濡れてることだよ
豪快な全開ヒルクライムが見たかったのにな
I wanted to see their
dynamic full-throttle hill climb.
It's a battle between fast cars, but
they can't open the throttle too much.
せっかく速い車どうしのバトルなのに　アクセル開けられないし　トップスピードも出ないバトルになっちまうよ
It means we won't see
their top speeds in this race.
いや　そんなことはないだろう
No, I don't think so.
トップスピードは出なくても　ハイレベルな技術の応酬になると思うし
Even if they don't reach their top speed,
it'll be an exchange of high-level skills.
このコンディションだと　車もただパワーが出ればいいってものじゃなく
Under these conditions, those cars are required to
have a high level of total balance, instead of power.
トータルバランスの高さの勝負になるだろう
見方によっては通好みの　かなりおもしろいバトルになると思うよ
Depending on how you look at it, it's going to be an
interesting battle that will excite those with sophisticated eyes.
全く腹立たしいぜ　今日の雨は
The rain pisses me off.
せっかく馬力をあげて太いタイヤをはいても　路面が濡れてちゃうまみがねんだ
If the road is wet, it's pointless to have
increased power and fatter tires.
It stopped raining, so the surface should become
somewhat dryer by the time the hill climb is over.
ヒルクライムが終わるまでにいくらか乾くんじゃないですか
雨はやんだから
できるだけ池田には時間を稼いでもらいたいな
I hope Ikeda's race drags
on for as long as possible.
路面は乾けば乾くほど　おれの戦いが有利になるからな
The drier the surface gets,
the easier it is for me to race.
おお　池田は先攻ですか　このコンディションで先攻とは
It looks like Ikeda chose to be the lead.
But why did he do that
under these conditions ?
246の小早川も　片桐の皆川も　後追いで負けているからな
Both Kobayakawa of 246 and Minagawa
of Katagiri were defeated as the chaser.
その流れを嫌ったかな
Maybe he's trying to break that jinx.
Generally speaking, the lead driver will feel
enormous pressure at the beginning of a wet race.
しかし雨のレースでは　スタート直後に先頭走るドライバーには　かなりのプレッシャーがかかるもんです
路面の状態を探りながら　ペースを作らんといけませんからな　公道でも同じことがいえるでしょう
The driver has to build his pace while
trying to figure out the road conditions.
It's the same for a street race.
精神力の強い男ですな　スパイラルのゼロは
Spiral's Zero has strong mettle.
俺達スパイラルは車づくりを重視したチームだと思われている
People think we, team Spiral,
are focused on tuning cars.
事実　チューニングには拘っている　けど　闇雲に金を注ぎ込んでるわけじゃない
It's true that we're picky about tuning, but
it's not like we spend our money aimlessly.
改造の方向性に拘るのがスパイヤルのスタイルなんだ
It's Spiral's style to focus on
the approach of modification.
車そのものがドライバーに乗り方を限定して要求してくるような　明確な意思をもった車づくり
We build cars with clear objectives, as if
the car demands a particular driving style.
それがゼロ理論の基本なんだ
That's the basics of Zero theory.
人の心というのは弱いものだ
The human mind is weak...
なぜなら感情があり
...because of emotions.
感情は冷静な判断と正確な操作の邪魔をする
Emotions hinder sound judgment and precise control.
たとえばこの雨にぬれたコンディション　アクセルを踏み込めない焦りやフラストレーション
For example, this rainy condition...
It causes frustration by not being able to step on the
gas, as well as anxiety and fear of the slippery road.
滑る路面に対する不安や恐れ
そうした人間の持つあらゆる感情は　必ずミスを生む
Those human emotions will lead to a mistake.
すべての感情を無心の状態で　車が語りかけてくる声を聞く
So you have to empty your mind
and listen to the voice of your car.
ゼロ理論は車との対話から始まるんだ
Zero theory begins by
interacting with your car.
He's not just skilled, he's amazing.
うまいっていうか　すげーな　こいつ
He's so stable on this wet surface.
Is he trying not to skid the tires ?
こんな濡れた路面で全くふら付かない
ホイルスピンをさせてないのか
かといって攻めてないわけじゃない
But that doesn't mean he's driving slow.
その証拠に　ついていく俺は結構ふらふらだからな
As proof of that, in just trying to keep up,
I'm almost losing control of my car.
アクセル操作に無駄がないってことか
Does that mean he doesn't have
any wasteful accelerator work ?
その気負いのなさが不気味だぜ
His lack of eagerness is eerie.
まさに壁だな　高橋弟がゼロをどう攻め落とすのか
The younger Takahashi is facing a wall...
...but there's plenty of time to
see how he tries to fight Zero.
じっくりと見せてもらおうか
よくできた車というのはそれ自体が意志を持っている
A well-tuned car has its own soul...
だからこそドライバーは謙虚になるべきだ
...so the driver should be modest.
車を操ろうとするのではなく　車と一体になってその意志に従うだけでいい
Instead of trying to manage the car...
...make yourself part of the car
and drive as the car wishes.
怒り　不安　焦り　それらの感情はネガティブな結果だけをもたらすものであり
Emotions like anger, anxiousness,
and haste will cause a negative result.
闘争心さえも　ゼロの発進には不要だ
Even fighting spirit is unnecessary for Zero driving.
そもそも　ゼロ理論ってどういうものなんだ
What is Zero theory exactly ?
It sounds really ambiguous and
I don't even know if I get it or not.
なんか抽象的すぎてわかったような　分からないような
俺の解釈では　ミスをしないことを優先した理論だと思う
My interpretation is that it's a
theory of prioritizing fewer mistakes.
Instead of letting drivers do as they like...
ドライバーは主体的な存在ではなく　車そのものに意志があると考え
...assume cars have wills of their own,
and let the drivers follow them.
ドライバーのほうがその意志に従っていくという考え方だ
そこがわかったような分からないようなところなんだよ
That's the part I'm not sure about.
少し極端な言い方をすれば　感情のないコンピューターが車をコントロールしている状態を　一つの理想と考えて
To put it in extreme terms, they assume an emotionless
computer-controlled car as an ideal example...
ドライバーの意識や感情を消していくことだろう
...then they try to suppress the
driver's consciousness and emotion.
アプローチとしては間違っていない
Such an approach isn't wrong.
ミスは百パーセント人の心から生まれるものだからな
Mistakes are always
caused by human emotions.
車との対話の重視
I agree with the idea of focusing
on the interaction with the car...
それは俺も同じ考えだ　藤原と86の関係のようにな
...like the relationship between
Fujiwara and his Eight-Six.
A driver's skills are determined by the amount
and accuracy of information he receives.
いかに多くの正確なインフォメーションをキャッチできるかで　ドライバーの技量は決まる
特にこの滑りやすい状況だと　タイヤからのインフォメーションは生命線だ
Especially with wet road conditions like this,
the information from the tires is crucial.
すきのない相手か
So our opponent has no weakness ? Is there
any way we can break through his defenses ?
それで突破口はあるのか
ある
There is.
人間である限り　感情を完璧にコントロールすることなんて　不可能だ
It's impossible for a human to
completely control his emotions.
I won't be fooled.
俺は騙されない
In Zero theory even fighting spirit is
regarded as unnecessary, but that's not true.
ゼロ理論では　闘争心さえも不要ということになっているが
そこは違う
どっしりとした安心感
Very safe and stable.
I don't like that type.
やりにくいぜこのタイプ
ものすごいテクニシャンだ
He's an incredible technician since he's
picking up the pace under these conditions.
こんなコンディションでペースを上げてきている
ドライバーは速くなるために絶対必要なもの
There's something absolutely
necessary for a driver to drive fast.
俺と啓介の今回のキーワードは　闘争心だ
The key word between Keisuke and I is...
...fighting spirit.
本当に現実になってきたな
Yesterday, you mentioned a worse condition
than the rain, and now it's become real.
昨日久保さんが言っていた　雨以外にもう一つの最悪な状況に
箱根名物　白い悪魔
Hakone's infamous...
...white demon.
霧だと
Fog ?!
ゴール近くにいる奴らからの連絡によると
According to the guys near the peak,
it's getting thicker and thicker.
上のほうからどんどん濃くなってるらしい
冗談じゃねーぞ
This's ridiculous.
We're in the middle of a hill climb race.
ヒルクライムの真っ最中なのに
This's horrible.
最悪だぜ
富士スピードウェイなら即刻レッドフラグで走行中止だぜ
If this was the Fuji Speedway, the race would
be immediately terminated with a red flag.
これ以上濃くならないことを祈るしかないだろう
We can only hope the fog
doesn't get any thicker.
最低限の視界さえ確保できていれば
So long as he has good enough visibility...
...a seasoned driver like Ikeda
should be able to manage.
百戦錬磨の池田さんなら なんとかしてくれる
だけど これでコースのあっちこっちに立たせてある　見方のマーシャルは役に立てなくなるな
But our race marshals scattered throughout the
course will be useless because you can't see them.
見えなくなるんじゃな
それも仕方ないよ
That can't be helped.
In any case, no driver can
maintain their pace in the fog.
どっち道 霧の中でペースを落とさずに走れるドライバーなんて　いやしないんだ
この霧を予測してたっていうのか
You anticipated this fog ?
I knew this weekend's weather would be bad.
この週末に天候が崩れるのは　事前の予報でわかっていたからな
箱根に乗り込む前に
Before coming to Hakone, I gathered as much historical
data as possible about the relationship between rain and fog.
可能の限り過去のデータを集めて
雨と霧の相関関係を調べてみたんだ
I see.
I predicted that this fog was highly probable.
ほう　今日の条件では　高い確率で霧が出ることは予想できた
あらかじめ啓介にもそれは伝えてある
I told Keisuke about it beforehand.
俺たちははじめから　この霧を前提にして作戦を考えていたんだ
We took this fog into account
when we planned our strategy.
開いた口がふさがらないよ
You're just amazing.
Normally people wouldn't notice that.
普通じゃちょっと考え付かない
But, Ryosuke, this poor visibility
affects both drivers equally.
だけど　涼介　視界が悪くなるのは　どっちにとっても同じ条件なわけだし
そうなれば コースを知ってる地元のほうが有利なんじゃないのか
If that's the case, don't you think
the local driver has an advantage ?
それはどうかな
I don't know about that.
Fog...
霧だ
恐ろしい
That's scary.
霧の中から飛び出してきて 霧の中へと消えていく
They popped out and disappeared into the fog.
ぶっ飛んでるよ どっちも
They're both out of their minds. How can
they keep their foot on the pedal in this fog ?
霧の中であんなにアクセル踏めるもんなのか
このエリアーの一番の特徴は
This area's most notable feature is the
famous Fuji Speedway in their territory.
富士スピードウェイという国内でも有数のサーキットがバックグランドにあることだろうな
There's no doubt it's helping
the locals improve their skills.
それが走りのレベルを引き上げていることは間違いない
来てる
This is it. The situation is developing
just like my brother predicted.
兄貴が予想した方向に向かってる
思っていたより早く攻撃のチャンスが来る
My chance to attack will come sooner than expected.
I won't miss this window of opportunity.
その一瞬を絶対に逃がさない
必然的に走りも車もサーキットを強く意識したものになっていく
Naturally, their cars and driving
styles are biased toward the circuit.
そりゃそうだろうな
Probably so.
池田のゼロ理論を読んでいて 俺はそれを強く感じたんだ
I felt that strongly when
I read Ikeda's Zero theory.
安心して走れる環境が整った　クローズドサーキット向けの発想など
His idea is suitable for a closed circuit, an
environment designed to be used for safe driving.
それはそのまま峠に応用できる優れた理論であることは確かだけど
It's a superb theory that you can
apply to mountain passes, but...
不測の事態が起こることに対応していない
...it doesn't take uncertainties into account.
こうなると 一本目先攻の選択は正解だったとは言えないが
Now I must admit that my choice of taking
the lead for the first run was wrong.
だけど バトルをしているからには
But the battle is still on. I want to keep
the drop in my pace to a minimum.
ペースダウンは最小限に留めたい
明らかに俺は慌てている
It's obvious that I'm getting upset.
ゼロ理論の基本 車との対話がどれほどできていても
Interaction with the car
is the basic of Zero theory.
それだけでは切り抜けられない
But no matter how well I do it,
I can't break free from this situation.
この視界の悪さは俺でも怖い
Even I'm scared of this poor visibility.
But it will wear out the lead more.
だけど ペースを作る先攻のほうが消耗する
さっきから一つだけはっきり変わったことがある
There's one clear difference from earlier.
I couldn't see any sign of emotion before,
but now I do on the rear of Zero's car.
全く見えなかった感情の起伏が　ゼロの背中にチラホラと見え始めてるぜ
俺が考える公道の最速理論はもっとえげつないぜ
My theory of fastest street driving is even dirtier.
I've been making Keisuke practice a type of
blind training inspired by Fujiwara's blind attack.
藤原のブラインドアタックをヒントにしたブラインドトレーニングを　日頃から啓介にもやらせている
本当かよ
Really ?
It wasn't really meant for fog.
霧対策というわけじゃなかったが
But our solution to temporary low visibility
at night in the rain will come in handy.
夜の雨で著しく視界が悪化した時の対策が役に立つ
いいか　坂本
Listen, Sakamoto, if you feel fear,
ease up on the gas pedal.
怖いと感じたら アクセルを抜くんだ
それはゼロの心の基本中の基本だ
It's the basics of the Zero mindset.
恐怖心に身がすくむとき　人間は必ずパニックになる
When we're petrified with fear,
we tend to panic.
そもそも怖いと感じるような事態に陥ることがすでにミスだ
If you feel fear, you've
already made a mistake.
そんなときにアクセルを抜いて 冷静さを取り戻せ
When it happens, release the gas
pedal, and calm yourself down.
恐怖心を抱えたまま突っ走ることは命取りだぜ
You're risking your life if you
drive with fear. Don't forget that.
忘れるなよ
From here on, it's a fight against fear.
ここから先の領域は恐怖心との戦いだ
プラスアルファの感情がいやでも走りを支配する
Extra emotions will dictate your driving style.
なんだ　この不快な感じは
What's this uncomfortable feeling ?
A part of me is telling me
to ease up on the throttle.
俺の心がアクセルを抜けと言ってるんだ
But another self is refusing,
keeping my foot on the pedal.
だけど それに逆らって もう一人の俺がアクセルを踏んでいる
そのチグハグな感じがストレスなんだ
That contradiction is causing stress.
But I can't lose.
でも 負けるわけにはいかない
What I need now is focus and....
今のおれに何より必要なものは集中力だ
それと　勝ちたいと強く思う気持ち
...a strong desire to win.
それはおれが普段否定しているもの
It's that fighting spirit...
...which I normally deny.
つまり 闘争心
プロジェクトＤは純度百パーセントの公道アタッカーだ
Project D consists of pure street attackers.
霧でも何でも 勝つためには使わせてもらうさ
Whether it's fog or whatever, we'll
do what we need to in order to win.
走行ラインが違う
His line is different.
Clearly different from
earlier in the battle.
明らかにバトル序盤とは違う
なんてことだ
I can't believe this. Am I not
racing with the mindset of Zero ?
今の俺はゼロの心で戦っていないのか
I can tell from his line that he's
concerned about oncoming traffic.
たぶんこれは対向車の存在を意識したラインだ
この視界でいきなり対向車が現れたらかわせないからな
In this visibility, there's no way
you can avoid an oncoming car.
He must have arranged a number of
course marshals at the blind corners.
おそらくブライドコーナーにコースマーシャルは何人もたたせていたんだろう
それがこの霧で役に立たなくなっている
But now they're useless because of this fog.
兄貴の読みがどんぴしゃだぜ
Brother's prediction was dead on.
Not yet ?
まだか
This place should do it.
ここがいいだろう
This is where the average speed suddenly
increases after a series of slow sections.
だらだらとした低速セクションを抜けて　アベレージスピードがぽんと羽上がるところだ
兄貴の予想通り霧が出れば
If the fog forms as
my brother predicted...
どんな強い人間でもアクセルを踏みこむことを躊躇してしまう
...anyone would hesitate to step on the
gas no matter how strong-minded he is.
The idea is to pick an overtake location and
practice repeatedly until you can visualize it.
ピンポイントにオーバーテイクのラインを想定して
ひたすら反復練習でそれをイメージに焼き付けるんだ
I don't know how thick the fog will become...
霧がどこまで濃くなるのか　今はわからないけど
...but I've practiced until I could
trace the line with my eyes closed.
目をつぶっていてもラインがトレースできるくらいになるまで走りこむ
Your role during the actual race is important.
I'm counting on you, Kenta.
本番でのお前の役目は重要だからな
頼むぜ ケンタ
啓介さんは目を瞑ったり開いたりを繰り返しながらこの区間を何度も往復してた
Keisuke went back and forth on this
section with his eyes open and closed.
That was how he trained to avoid
dropping his pace in poor visibility.
あれは視界が悪くてもペースを落とさずに走るトレーニングだ
天は啓介さんに見方していると考えていいのか
Is it okay to believe that the
heavens are on Keisuke's side ?
この霧の深さは想定外なんじゃないのか
Wasn't fog this thick within his expectations ?
こんな状況でパッシングだなんて
Passing in this fog sounds so suitable for
the bold Keisuke, but it's too dangerous.
あんまりにも大胆で啓介さんらしいけど
危険すぎる
Their exhaust sounds are close.
He'll reach the planned location soon.
排気音はもう近くまで来てる
予定のポイントにもうすぐさしかかる
だけど　重要なのは背中からの音だよな
But what's more important
is any sound from behind.
責任重大　啓介さんのためにもミスは許されない
I have a great responsibility.
For Keisuke sake, I can't make a mistake.
すごいね 　シンちゃん 　スパイヤルの池田って
Isn't that incredible, Shin ?
Spiral's Ikeda drives so fast in this fog.
この霧の中であんなにアクセルを踏んでる
I don't know about that.
そうかな　後ろの背の低い車のほうがすごいよ
The lower car in the rear
seemed more amazing.
It looked like a yellow fireball to me, Mom.
僕にはまるで黄色い火の球みたいに見えたよ　母さん
この先は林間を抜けて 丘陵地帯に差し掛かる
We'll leave the woods and reach a hilly area soon.
霧が薄ければ 右サイドに視界が開ける
Once the fog gets thinner, I should
be able to see the right lane clearer.
そこまでいけば　これまでの欝憤を一気に晴らす
Then I'll be able to let out my frustration...
...at full throttle.
アクセル全開だ
霧　見えない 何も
Fog...?!
I can't see anything...
A white void !
白い闇だ
Incoming call...
着信あり
...which means no oncoming
traffic in the target area.
目標エリアに対向車なし
ナイス ケンタ ジャスタイミング
Nice Kenta. Perfect timing.
恐ろしいぜ どんなに強く脳が命令を下しても
This is scary.
No matter how strongly my brain commands
me to do it, my intuition is firmly refusing it.
本能がそれを頑なに拒絶する
Fujiwara Takumi:
Takahashi Ryosuke:
Takahashi Keisuke:
Ikeda Ryuji:
Hojo Gou:
Kubo Eiji:
Kenta:
Fumihiro:
Miki Shinichiro
Koyasu Takehito
Seki Tomokazu
Nakai Kazuya
Kiuchi Hidenobu
Kase Yasuyuki
Okano Kosuke
Hosoi Hajime
日の暮れに　変わらない景色
Even when night falls, the scenery remains unchanged.
Takeuchi Itsuki:
Iketani Koichiro:
Kenji:
Okuyama Hiroya:
Inui Shinji:
Shinji's Mom:
Mechanic:
Iwata Mitsuo
Yao Kazuki
Takagi Wataru
Sakaguchi Shuhei
Abe Atsushi
Hirose Yuuka
Takahashi Ryokichi
振り返る　辿ってきた道
Looking back at the path I've taken.
切なさも　喜びも　消えない痛みも
Sadness, happiness, incurable pains...
Realizing that there are too many to count, as I walk alone.
数えてたら限がないねと独り歩く
A
Central Anime
Production
Translation:
Hiro-kun
Timing:
Todd Perkins
Editing:
Lillian-Hime
Barbara
Todd Perkins
Brain
Dave
Mouse
Steve S.
Nomake
Countless number of memorable scenes.
数え切れないほどの残像　ギャンブル生き抜いてきた残党
We lived through the hustle and bustle.
時に戦い　時に解りあい　きれい事ばかりじゃなかった真実
Sometimes we argued, sometimes we understood.
It wasn't always pretty, but I keep the truth to myself...
背負ったまま新たな一歩
...as I take a new step.
あかね雲が街を染める　この行く先をそっと問いかけて見る
Rosy clouds embellish the city.
I quietly ask about my future.
空はなにもいわず　だけど私にこの道を照らしている
The sky remains silent.
Only illuminating this path before me.
透き通る景色を感じて
Feel the translucent scenery.
旋律を夕陽が奏で
The setting sun plays a melody.
透き通る景色を感じて
Feel the translucent scenery.
The setting sun plays a melody.